Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2004
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Haupt, Irene
1 box (44 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 44 photographs of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2004 at the University at Buffalo.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2005.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
All images are available in the UB Libraries Digital Collections as part of the overall June in Buffalo Collection.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2004 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004 contains 44 images of participants in the festival for 2004. The list of musicians includes David Felder, Ed Campion, Tristan Murail, Horacio Vaggione, Roger Reynolds, Cort Lippe, Jeffrey Stadelman, Tod Machover, Rand Steiger, and Zack Settel.
Arrangement
One sequence of images in alphabetical order by principal subject of the image.
Container List
- Photographs, June 2004, I.
  - Ed Campion at computer, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 01)
  - Ed Campion at computer, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02)
  - David Felder, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 03)
  - David Felder profile, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 04)
  - David Felder, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05)
  - David Felder at sound console, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 06)
  - David Felder with Rand Steiger (left), and Paul Kugler (right), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 07)
  - Lars Graugaard at computer, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 08)
  - Lars Graugaard at computer, and Tom Stoll (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09)
  - Mara Helmuth, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
  - Cort Lippe, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Tod Machover, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
  - Tod Machover and Roger Reynolds (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Tod Machover and Roger Reynolds (left background), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Tod Machover and Jonathan Golove (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Tod Machover and Jonathan Golove (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Tod Machover and Jonathan Golove (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Tod Machover and Jonathan Golove (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Magnus Martensson, conductor and Patti Monson, flutist, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Tristan Murail, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Tristan Murail and Rand Steiger (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Tristan Murail, Jeffrey Stadelman, unidentified student, and Rand Steiger, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Marilyn Nonken, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Takayuki Rai, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Roger Reynolds, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Roger Reynolds, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Roger Reynolds, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Roger Reynolds, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Roger Reynolds and Tristan Murail, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Roger Reynolds and Satoshi Tanaka (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Robert Rowe, Cort Lippe, Roger Reynolds, Satashi Tanaka, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Unidentified student, Tristan Murail, Cort Lippe, Horatio Vaggione, Roger Reynolds, Satashi Tanaka, Robert Rowe, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Robert Rowe, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 33)
  - William Sack, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Trond Saeverud, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Zack Settel, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Zack Settel and Cort Lippe (left), June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Rand Steiger, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Rand Steiger and Marianne Gythfeld, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Satashi Tanaka, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Horatio Vaggione, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Horatio Vaggione, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Horatio Vaggione and Ake Parmerud, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Ji Hyun Woo, June 2004, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 44)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 18
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2000 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2001 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2002 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2003 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2005 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2011 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.